# **Christopher Wallace**

Chief Design Officer & Lead Designer

I work with companies like DC Comics, Starbucks, Google, and even The California DMV to transform the digital product experience for millions of people worldwide. My approach to design is collaborative, reducing technical complexity to simple, delightful experiences for everyday users.

portfolio <u>chriswallace.net</u>

email <u>chriswallace7@pm.me</u>

linkedin linkedin.com/in/chriswallace2

phone +1 972 837 7267

address 6400 Orchard Park Drive, McKinney, TX 75071

## **Work Experience**

#### **Lead Product Designer**

Mar 2024 - Oct 2024

Candy Digital — McKinney, TX

- Designed features for a digital collectible marketplace
- Created product prototypes in Figma and with code
- Created a design system and helped integrate it into Storybook
- Collaborated cross-functionally to execute major organizational initiatives

#### **Chief Design Officer**

Apr 2021 - Mar 2024

UltraDAO Studios — McKinney, TX

- Co-founded a web3 creative studio for entertainment media IP, digital products and blockchain-based collectibles
- Managed a team of digital artists and creatives
- Bootstrapped revenue from zero to \$2.6 million in six months

#### VP, Experience Design

Aug 2017 - Sep 2021

10up — McKinney, TX

- Managed a team of 20+ design leaders and visual, UX, and content designers internationally
- Led design projects for Starbucks, Microsoft, Facebook, Google, and more.
- Established design quality standards, addressing process and crossfunctional collaboration issues
- Crafted vision for design organization-wide and within specific client portfolio accounts

#### **Principal Creative Director**

Dec 2009 - Aug 2017

Lift UX — McKinney, TX

- Managed a small design and engineering team
- Led design of second screen companion apps for The Walking Dead,
  Breaking Bad, Mad Men, and more.
- Created digital products for WordPress including plugins, themes, and developer tools

### Front-End Developer

Aug 2007 - Dec 2009

Enterprise Rent-A-Car — Clayton, MO

- Wrote the front-end code for B2B and B2C products including enterprise.com
- Worked cross-functionally with UX Architects and Java engineers to plan design integrations
- Managed weekly deployments and performed visual QA

#### Senior E-Commerce Web Designer

May 2006 - Aug 2007

Network Solutions - Belleville, IL

- Designed and developed e-commerce shops for small businesses, focusing on user-friendly interfaces
- Collaborated with clients daily to plan and design store templates
- Worked closely with logo designers to implement brand assets

## **Education**

#### Missouri State University

2004

Graphic Design

#### Saint Louis Christian College

2002 - 2004

General and Religious Studies

## **Technical Skills**

Figma, design systems, design research, product design, mobile/iOS/Android, design engineering, Rive, Framer, Webflow, Storybook, CSS, Svelte, React, Next.js, Web3, blockchain, responsive design, accessibility

## **Awards**

- Award: Best Environmental Initiative from an NFT project NFT NYC (2022)
- Nominee: Outstanding Creative Achievement in Interactive Media Social
  TV Experience, Mad Men: The Fan Cut Emmy Awards (2015)
- Nominee: Outstanding Interactive Program, The Walking Dead Story Sync –
  Emmy Awards (2013)
- Award: Best Second Screen App, The Walking Dead Story Sync Variety Awards (2012)